Lee Alan Burton

Personal Details

Nationality: British Place of Birth: U.K.

Email Address: leeburton@shu.edu.cn Twitter Handle: @leeaburton

Office Telephone: +86 021 6613 6129 Website: www.bmd-lab.org

Office Address: E111, Baoshan Campus, Shanghai University, Shanghai, 200444, China.

Google Scholar Page: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=fEp-jzkAAAAJ&hl=en

Linkedin Profile: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/lee-a-burton/ **ORCiD:** 0000-0002-0647-5483

Professional Summary

Status: Associate Professor (full time).

Affiliations: Member of the Royal Society of Chemistry.

Accolades: - Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award 2019.

- Shanghai Municipal Government Eastern Young Scholar Award 2018.

- European Commission Seal of Excellence Award 2017.

- Japanese Material Research Society Award for Encouragement of Materials

Science 2012.

Publications: 24 peer-review research articles; 4 international patents covering 13 inventions.

Metrics: More than 1,700 citations, h-index: 16, 4 first-author papers with >130 citations. **Funding Awards:** Early career fellowship, 2 International Research Fellowships, PhD Scholarship.

Languages: English (native), French (conversational), Mandarin (basic).

Qualifications

Doctoral Qualification: PhD in Sustainable Chemical Technologies, University of Bath, UK.

Undergraduate Degree: Master of Chemistry (Hons), University of Warwick, UK.Other Qualifications: Master of Research (Merit), University of Bath, UK.

Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (B1), Université Catholique de Louvain.

Key Skills Summary (Colours for Cross-Reference)

- Project management, team-leading, task delegation and international collaboration.
- Programming proficiency in Python 2/3, Bash and LaTeX languages, computer and numerical literacy.
- Project proposal and persuasive writing.
- Control of Substances Hazardous to Health (COSHH), risk assessment and lab management.
- Budget management, resource allocation and account keeping.
- Multi-disciplinary teamwork, conference and event organisation.
- International communication, presentation and public engagement.
- 3D visualisation software, image rendering and data plotting.
- Teaching, lecturing, online recording and teleconferencing.

Employment History

Feb. 2019 to Present – Associate Professor, Shanghai University, China.

- Recipient of Shanghai Eastern Young Scholar early career fellowship, 2019.
- Recipient of the Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award, 2019.
- Tenured faculty position in the dept. of physics and guest lecturer in dept. of international development.
- More than 100 lecturing hours to date with both graduate and undergraduate students.
- Tutorial leader at the 2019 Jiangsu mathematics & computing in materials design graduate summer school.
- Invited speaker at two international conferences and one international workshop.
- Recipient of Royal Society of Chemistry small equipment research fund, 2020.
- One (Chinese) group member to date offered fully-funded PhD scholarships in the USA.
- 5 research papers published to date including invited article selected as cover for J. Mat. Chem. C. emerging investigators special issue 2020 and contributed article selected as cover for J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2020.

Dec. 2016 to Feb. 2019 – Research Fellow, Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium.

Lee Alan Burton

- Recipient of "Move-In Louvain" research fellowship funded by the EU Marie-Curie actions.
- Recipient of the European Commission Seal of Excellence award 2018.
- Invited speaker & session chair at European Materials Research Society (E-MRS) Meetings 2017 & 2018.
- B1 level Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (DELF) qualification obtained.
- 2 international patents granted, contribution purchased by Panasonic Corporation.
- Tutorial leader on database querying & high-throughput screening at Materials Research Society (MRS) Spring Meeting, USA, 2018.

Nov. 2014 to Nov. 2016 –Research Fellow, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Japan.

- Royal Society nominee for fully funded Japanese Society for Promotion of Science (JSPS) fellowship.
- Equal shareholder on international patent for 11 novel semiconductors (number WO/2017/065294).
- Speaker at four international conferences and invited contribution to international workshop.
- 5 research articles published in high impact journals including Nature Comms. and Phys. Rev. Lett.
- Volunteer participant of JSPS Science Dialogue program: lecturing at senior high schools (ages 15-17).

Oct. 2010 to Oct. 2014 - Doctoral Student, University of Bath, UK.

- Multi-disciplinary PhD funded by Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council scholarship.
 - Recipient of Award for Encouragement of Materials Science by Japanese Materials Research Society.
 - Over 2,000 GBP in external grant money and bursary awards.
- Laboratory custodian of Solar Instrument Room, Department of Chemistry.
 - Developed control and safety standards for contemporary lab space.
 - Implemented training and operating protocols for hazardous experimental procedures.
- Public engagement and ambassadorial roles for the Centre for Sustainable Chemical Technologies.
 - Elected Ambassador to the UK Energy Research Network for the Bath graduate school.
 - Invited speaker for the British Science Association's 'Science Café' public presentation.
 - University of Bath STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) ambassador.
- Taught-lab demonstrator and part-time teaching assistant.

Dec. 2013 to May 2014 – Events Manager, "Pint of Science" festival, Bath, UK.

Theme leader of 'Planet Earth' section, Bath chapter, for international science festival 'Pint of Science'.

Nov. 2013 to Apr. 2014 - Conference Organiser, Royal Society of Chemistry, UK.

- Organising committee member for the RSC, Solid State Group Easter Meeting, Buckinghamshire, UK.
- Responsibilities included: budget allocations, costing, talk selection and program design.

Jul. 2013 to Dec. 2013 – Visiting Scholar, Harvard University, USA.

- Established collaboration between the University of Bath (UK), Harvard University (USA) and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (USA).
- Involved multiple visits between UK & USA, confidential data handling and regular teleconferencing.

Oct. 2010 to Sep. 2011 - Master of Research, University of Bath, UK.

• Degree with taught courses and 2 research projects: battery cathodes and materials for hydrogen storage.

Apr. 2009 to Sep. 2009 – Research Intern, University of Tasmania, Australia.

• Designed and built a 2-D gas chromatography suite to analyse oil spills for the Australian Antarctic Division.

Suggested Referees

Professor Aron Walsh, (PhD Supervisor) Royal School of Mines, Imperial College London, London, SW7 2BP, United Kingdom. a.walsh@imperial.ac.uk

Professor Fumiyasu Oba (Post-Doctoral Supervisor) Laboratory for Materials & Structures, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Yokohama 226-8503, Japan. oba@msl.titech.ac.ip

Professor Jeffrey Reimers (Current Institute Director) School of Mathematical and Physical Sciences, University of Technology Sydney, Sydney, Australia. jeffrey.reimers@uts.edu.au